So this is a long one, and aren't you tired yet? Got some conflict fatigue going on? Feeling like
everything is hopeless? Futile like your government is completely compromised and doesn't give a damn
about what you think? Cool. Well, strap in because the Vietnam War took 10 years of activism, with
millions of Americans showing up to demonstrations involved in corporate boycotts, social organizing,
capitalist divestment, and conscientious voting to end the damn thing. And this isn't ending
anytime soon. A ceasefire is elusive but inevitable, but there will be a years-long
humanitarian crisis. Gaza will have to be rebuilt without Israel, Saudi, the UAE, or all three
installing a puppet government in the Strip so they can exploit the Gaza Marine Basin and displace the
population. There is also the threat of a sustained security operation by the IDF in conjunction with
a settlement initiative, which will probably be inflamed under Trump. This seems the most likely
inevitability, and of course the resistance will still exist, and whatever truce Israel makes that
the Biden administration blesses will be a bad faith truce, and violence is liable to flare up
at any moment over the next years. The talking point of a two-state solution will be in contention for a
long while, but it will prove unworkable. Then a genocidal apartheid regime will have to be dismantled,
so that's gonna be a whole damn thing. And on and on and on. So 10 years would be fucking optimistic.
So if you're like, well, I can't keep doing this for 10 years, yeah, you're right. You're gonna have
to learn how to resume your life while normalizing divestment and resistance and spreading awareness,
because if people are ignorant now, they're gonna be ignorant in five years. Look, you already live in a
dystopia, probably working a job you hate just because you get health insurance and the off chance that if
something happens, you'll be able to, like, not die. But now your eyes are open to how imperialism
works and how it completely screws you too if you're not part of the top 1%, and there's no putting
that gin back in the bottle. So remember that social life you had in September, remember those
hobbies, it's time to resume them and add to them, because what's one of your new hobbies?
Showing up to protest, rallies, banner drops, sit-ins, and also not buying Israeli crap. And continue to
annoy the shit out of complacent, lazy liberals who don't get to espouse liberal values when Israel
literally violates everyone, because, you know, liberal values are inherently supremacist. So 10
years, plan on it, plan on more, but I will say global shifts happen a lot faster now than they did
during Vietnam. So continue to stay informed, tune into it, interact with social media, don't beat
yourself up, show up when you're supposed to show up. You already know what you're supposed to be
doing, just do it in a sustainable way, because the man is banking on your conflict fatigue.
Then you'll just get too burnt out from the horror and the futility of doom-scrolling atrocity for six
months and say, fuck it, and just go away. So for what it's worth, resume your life,
normalize resistance, even if it's small, and I'll see you on the next one.